Guide to the Orrin Leslie Elliott Correspondence
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Orrin Leslie Elliott correspondence
1892-1914
SC0032
Elliott, Orrin Leslie, 1860-1940
1 Linear feet
Incoming and outgoing correspondence of Elliott as registrar, 1892-1914, regarding admissions, curriculum matters, fee structures, appointments, leaves, and administrative business; and general correspondence received by the University, 1891-1892, concerning academic and staff positions, business matters, and appointments. Correspondents include David Starr Jordan, John C. Branner, George E. Crothers, and George A. Clark.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1965.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Orrin L. Elliott was appointed president's secretary and registrar of Stanford University in June of 1891. He retired as registrar in 1925, but remained active as registrar emeritus.
Description of the Collection
Incoming and outgoing correspondence of Elliott as registrar for the years 1892 to 1914 and general correspondence received by the University, 1891-1892, generally addressed to Leland Stanford. Incoming correspondence to the Registrar includes letters from high schools and colleges concerning which of their courses are accredited for admission to Stanford and which of their students would be acceptable; inter-University letters concerning standing of students, admissions policies, curriculum matters, fee structures, appointments and leaves, Board of Trustee resolutions, and routine administrative business; and letters from students asking for leaves of absence and other matters. letters addressed to leland Stanford concern applications for academic and staff positions; business matters; purchases of books, shell collections, and other academic supplies; and appointments. Correspondents include David Starr Jordan, John C. Branner, George E. Crothers, and George A. Clark. There is also a file of correspondence from W. T. Reid of the Belmont School, 1897-1907.
Access Terms
Branner, John Casper, 1850-1922.; Clark, George A. (George Archibald), 1865-1918.; Crothers, George E. (George Edward), 1870-1957.; Elliott, Orrin Leslie, 1860-1940; Jordan, David Starr, 1851-1931; Stanford University. Registrar's Office.; Universities and colleges--Administration.; Universities and colleges--Admission.; Universities and colleges--Curricula.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Incoming correspondence: A-G, 1892-1902 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Incoming correspondence: H-M, 1892-1902 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Incoming correspondence: N-Z, 1892-1902 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Letterpress copybook of outgoing correspondence, 1892-1898 (Box 1)
  - Letters, L.S. Jr. University, Applications, 1891-1892 (Box 2)
  - Letters, L.S. Jr. University, General Received, 1891-1892 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence with w. T. Reid, May 1897 - September 1907 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1897-1905 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1906-1907 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1908-1909 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1910-March 1911 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, April 1911-1912 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1913-1914 (Box 3, Folder 7)